From Mangalore V.S.S.RAMGOPAL 26-08-2020

Vanashree, D.no 14-23-1432/2, 2nd floor (North portion), 15th Bendur Ward, Kadri village, Mangalore-575002

Phone No: +91- 8861851616

To

THE MANGER (HR)

Respected Sir,

Sub: Application for suitable post.

I wish to offer my candidature for the post of Manager in your organization. I have passed with first division in M.Sc. (Tech.) Instrumentation from Andhra University.

Presently working as a Manager (C&I) in M/s. Udupi Power Corporation Limited.

Having an overall experience of 23 years in operation and maintenance of different types of C&I field instruments and control equipments used in power plant in the areas of Boiler, Turbine and BOP like weigh feeders, Belt scales ,Pressure ,Flow, Level ,temperature transmitters, Control valves and on/off valves, PLC systems, SCADA ,DCS (Tata Honeywell TDC3000) ,Conveyor safety system ,Wagon loading system ,Fire fighting system, Stacker cum Reclaimer and Grab Ship unloaders.

Herewith, I am sending my detailed resume for your favorable consideration.

Thanking you sir,

Yours faithfully,

V.S.S.Ramgopal

CURRICULAM VITAE

NAME : V. S .S. RAMGOPAL

DATE OF BIRTH : 8th July 1967

CONTACT NO : +918861851616

TOTAL EXPERIENCE : 23 years

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

1. Master of Science (Tech) Instrumentation from Andhra University passed in First class in 1991.

2. Bachelor of Science (MPC) from Osmania University passed in First class in 1987.

Computer Skills: MS Office, DOS

TRAINING DETAILS:

Attended training program on APM IMPLEMENTATION Conducted by TATA HONEYWELL

Attended Internal Auditors Training Program on INTEGRATED MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

Professional Experience:

- 1. Working as a Manager in (C&I) in Udupi Power Corporation Limited, Mangalore from 31/10/2011.
- Working in Coal handling division and responsible for maintenance of various PLC systems like GE FANUC, ABB, MERIT, ALLEN BRADELY systems
- Review and approval of P&I Drawings, I/O lists, data sheets, cable schedules and JB details
- Involving in material receiving inspections and reviewing the test reports.
- Attend daily meetings and discuss various measures to improve plant efficiency and to implement new logics that can improve plant efficiency and safety.
- Taking of system backups and listing of spare I/O's for future requirements.
- Identification and maintenance of critical and general spares for plant needs.
- Actively participating in general/preventive maintenance, shutdown maintenance, and annual maintenance.
- Preparation and maintenance of ISO Documentation and facing quality audits by internal and external auditors.
- INSTRUMENTS AND SYSTEMS IN BRIEF:
- Ge fanuc Rx3i plc system 6.0 and SCADA 8.2 version for conveyor system
- ABB make AC 500 PLC systems for stacker cum reclaimer and slewing stacker

- ABB make AC 800M PLC system for Grab ship unloader
- Merit PLC for Wagon loading system
- Allen Bradley control logix 5561 PLC for Firefighting system
- Rice lake weighing systems for In motion weigh bridge
- 2. Worked in Rain CII carbon (VIZAG) Limited from August 1998 to September 2011
 - Actively participated in maintenance of 53.5 MW Co-generation plant consisting of medium pressure single extraction type 53.5 MW Turbine Generator supplied by ABB.
 - Circulated fluidized Bed Boiler (coke Fired) of rated steam pressure 63ksc and temperature around 485°c, supplied by Foster wheeler.
 - Waste heat recovery Boiler of rated steam pressure 64ksc, flow 110 T/Hr and temperature around 485°c supplied by Alsthom.
 - Waste heat recovery Boiler of rated steam pressure 63ksc, flow 105 T/Hr and temperature around 485°c supplied by American shack.
 - 2 x 750 T P D Rotating kilns and coolers supplied by F F E.
 - Ensured that all software's are updated in DCS & back-ups are kept in safe custody.
 - Ensured that all closed loop controllers in DCS are kept in AUTO Mode and checking the tuning parameters time to time according to the Process conditions.
 - INSTRUMENTS AND SYSTEMS IN BRIEF:
 - TDC 3000 Honeywell DCS System consisting of three Advanced Process Managers and three logic
 Managers and six universal stations.
 - Honeywell 620-36 PLC for de-mineralization plant and 620-16 PLC for boiler soot blowing system.
 - Allen Bradley PLC 5/40 for ash handling system, SLC 5/02 for WHB soot blowing system
 - Honeywell, Rosemount and CG&HG smart and analog transmitters.
 - Water analyzers': Honeywell, Rosemount, Forbes Marshall make PH, Conductivity, Dissolved
 Oxygen analyzers, Waltron make Sodium Analyser.
 - Various types of control and on-off valves of Valtek and Fisher.
 - Gas Analysers: Rosemount make so2
- 3. Worked in Indian Institute of Chemical Technology, Hyderabad from May 1994 to July 1998.
 - Worked as a Project Assistant and reporting to Project Manager. Actively involving in Project assignments like Neem and Custard Apple extracts . Analyzing various components in Neem and

Custard Apple seeds by analytical instruments like HPLC Systems. Analysis of the purity of the various components in the above samples. Maintenance of HPLC systems and Gas Chromatography systems.

4 Worked in INCORP, Hyderabad, from October 1991 to April 1994.

Worked as a Service Engineer. Frequently interacting with customers like Dr.Reddy's Labs, Natco Phrama, Chemito Drugs, Hetero Drugs, Indian Institute of Chemical Technology etc. Handled various analytical instruments like High Performance Liquid Chromatography Systems (HPLC), Gas Chromatography Systems, Centrifuges, Near Infra Red Analysers and Muffle Furnaces.

Reviewing and replying the enquiries and queries from customers.

Estimating the type of service required and cost of service and sending the quotations in coordinance with marketing Engineers.

PERSONAL DETIALS:

PERMANENT ADDRESS : K block, (flat # 302)

Varshini homes, Appannapalem

Visakhapatnam, A.P

MARTIAL STATUS : Married.

PRESENT C.T.C : INR 16 lakh per annum

EXPECTED SALARY : Negotiable